本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
现在我们回到吸金大转轮
We now return to cash wheel...
由薯味饼干赞助
sponsored by chipackerz.
薯片口味饼干
The chip-flavored crackers!
尝起来就像薯片一样
They taste just like chips!
恭喜  你获得了
Congratulations! You're taking a....
钞票淋浴
Cash shower!
我喜欢那家伙的风格
I like that guy's style.
派恩斯先生  九点钟方向有观光客
Mr. Pines! We got tourists at nine o'clock!
整整一巴士观光客
A whole busload of 'em!
正点  中大奖了
Hot tamales! It's a jackpot!
苏斯  做些新东西引人注意
Soos, make some new attractions!
没问题  老板
You got it, boss.
温蒂  把标价抬高  越高越好
Wendy, mark up those prices! The higher, the better!
再高点  榨干他们
Higher! Bleed 'em dry!
斯坦叔公
Sheesh, grunkle Stan,
似乎你一看到观光客
It's like when you look at tourists
就像看到了长着腿的钱包
All you see are wallets with legs.
没那回事
That's not true.
爸爸  谢谢你带我来神秘小屋
Thanks for taking me to the mystery shack, daddy.
哈哈  不要在一个地方把自己全花光哦
Ha ha! Now, don't spend yourself all in one place.
我觉得晕车了
I'm feeling car sick.
把门前的草坪打扫干净
Clean-up on the front lawn!
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录 www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： sunshine
翻译： Enpistu  Chamania
■
校订： Enpistu  WaitinZ
后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
怪诞小镇  第一季第十三集
Gravity Falls  S01E13  Boss Mabel
（多谢你的一分钱  -斯坦）
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentletourists,
在我的神秘小屋四处看看
Looking around my mystery shack,
你们会看到许多神奇的路边景观
you'll see many wondrous roadside attractions.
为这张不为人知的照片惊叹吧
Be amazed at the only known photo
一匹马骑着另一匹马
of a horse riding another horse.
那真是  真是太棒了
That's--that's pretty good.
哦  天哪
Ooh! Wow!
震惊吧  恐怖的青少年狼孩
Be astounded by the horrible pre-teen wolf boy!
看看他  看那些毛
Oh, look at him! All that hair!
他的身体在变化  嗷
His body is changing! Aaah!
斯坦叔公  这有点伤自尊啊
Grunkle Stan, this is demeaning.
什么  我不知道这个词的意思哦
What?! I don't know "Da meaning" of that word.
如果扔钱给他  他就会跳舞
If you throw money at him he dances.
哎呦  嘿
Ow! Hey!
哈哈  谢谢大家
Ha ha ha! Ooh! Ha ha! Thank you!
小心  神秘小屋保险杠贴纸
Behold! Mystery shack bumper stickers!
可以把它贴在你的汽车保险杠或者
You can stick 'em on your bumper or...
贴在你老公嘴上
Over your husband's mouth.
我说得对不对  女士们
Am I right, ladies?
她懂我的意思
She knows what I'm talkin' about.
小坏丫头  多少钱
You are bad. How much?
嘿  老板买单
Hey, it's on the house.
这是梅宝的特色
That's the Mabel difference.
-多谢光临  -什么
- Thanks for visiting! - What?!
你觉得你到底在干什么
What the heck do you think you're doing?
做生意  叮铃铃
Business! Ching, ching, ching!
听着  小鬼  把东西送出去可赚不了钱
Listen, kid, you don't make money by giving stuff away.
-不许再干收银的活儿了  -可是  可是
- You're off of register duty!  - But--but--
别“可是”了  马上到外面去
No "Buts" except yours out the door!
闭上你的嘴  快去工作
Now shut your yap and get to work!
斯坦叔公  你的“劳驾”和“谢谢”到哪里去啦
Grunkle Stan, whatever happened to "Please" And "Thank you"?
嗯  等一下
Hmm? Oh, wait.
在这儿呢
Here they are!
“劳驾”永远赚不来钱  小鬼
"Please" Never made me any money, kid.
事实上  只是说出这个词
In fact, just saying the word
我都会有火烧火燎的感觉
is giving me a burning sensation.
斯坦叔公  为什么我非得穿这件狼人装
Grunkle Stan, why do I have to wear this wolf costume?
我觉得都要得钩虫病了
I think I'm getting hookworm.
哈哈  对  把狗毛粘到身上的确会有这反应
Ha ha! Yep, gluing dog hair to your body will do that.
你小屋里的这些展览品全是拙劣的假货
You have all these dumb fake exhibits in the shack.
与此同时  我每天
Meanwhile, I've seen
都能在森林里见识神奇的真家伙
actual amazing things in the forest every day.
去捕捉真正的神奇生物怎么样
What if you hunted down a real attraction
不要再靠造假骗人来谋生了
instead of lying to people for a living?
而且你应该对你的员工更友善
And you should be nicer to your employees, too.
没错
Yeah!
看来  你们对我经营小屋的方式有点意见
Look, you guys got a problem with how I run the shack,
快把它提交给投诉部门
Take it up with the complaints department.
这里  哈哈哈
Zing! Ha ha ha!
我这就来给他们写投诉信
I am going to write them such a letter!
给招牌打满蜡之前不准停下来
And don't stop till you've covered that sign with glitter!
打蜡的招牌能吸引游客  也能引来大鸟
Glittery signs attract tourists! Also large birds.
哈哈  真好玩
Ha ha! That's funny.
好吧  是只有我这么觉得
Okay, is it just me, or is
还是有斯坦叔公这样的老板真是糟透了
having grunkle Stan as a boss seriously the worst?
我知道好吗  我们为什么要逆来顺受呢
I know, right? Why do we even put up with it?
我曾经试着给他提出改善小屋的建议
I tried to give him a suggestion to improve the shack once.
就是这个主意  可以由我来扮演
I had this idea where I could be,
类似  神秘小屋的吉祥物
like, the mystery shack mascot--
问号君“问问”
"Questiony the question mark."
我问人们问题
I ask people questions,
还可以跳跳提问舞
You know, do the question dance...
听起来很棒
That sounds amazing!
-很酷啊  -绝对的
- Oh, cool! - Yeah, totally!
是啊  唉  斯坦说我应付不来
Yeah, well, Stan said I couldn't handle it.
他说什么
He said what?!
要记住  伙计们
And remember, folks,
我们对您的快乐时光不予退款啊
We put the "Fun" In "No refunds"!
哈哈  冤大头
Ha ha! Suckers.
你
You!
斯坦叔公  你这次做得太过分了
Grunkle Stan, you've gone too far this time!
你竟然告诉苏斯不要追寻他的希望和梦想
Did you seriously tell Soos not to follow his hopes and dreams
还说他“应付不来”
because he "Couldn't handle it"?
听着  小鬼  我就简单给你解释一下
Look, kid, let me break it down for you.
作为老板就是要至高无上地掌管尊敬
Being a boss is about commanding respect.
如果你满足人们提出的一切要求
If you give people everything they ask for,
他们就会蹬鼻子上脸
they'll walk all over ya.
不可能  我敢打赌如果你能友善地对待别人
No way! I bet you'd make way more money being nice
肯定会比做一个脾气暴躁的怪老头赚到更多的钱
than being a big, grumpy grump to everyone all the time.
哈  你觉得你比我更懂怎么做生意
Ha! You think you know more about business than I do?
你觉得你能戴得了这顶帽子
You think you could wear this hat?
当然  因为我会给人们尊敬
Yeah, because I give people respect.
还有闪亮贴纸
And glittery stickers.
哈  我就算是去度假
Ha! I'd make more money on
赚的钱也比你经营这地方要多
vacation than you would running this place!
那你为什么不去度假呢
Then why don't you go on vacation?
有意思  好吧  我是个好赌的人
Interesting. All right, I'm a wagering man.
三天  七十二小时
Three days. 72 hours.
你来经营小屋  我去度假
You run the shack, and I'll go on vacation.
如果你赚的钱比我多
If you make more money than me,
我想那就意味着  你对我经营之道的看法是对的
I guess it means you're right about the way I run my business.
但是如果你输了
But if you lose,
你就得一整个夏天都穿着这件“失败者”衬衫
You gotta wear this "Loser" Shirt all summer. Ha ha!
好  但如果是我赢了
Fine! But if I win, I get
暑假剩下的时间里都由我当老板
to be the boss for the rest of the summer!
而且  你还要唱一首
Plus, you have to sing an
由我梅宝作词的道歉歌
apologizing song with lyrics by me, Mabel.
好啊  就算你成交  小姐
Oh ho! You got yourself a deal, missy!
不  就算你成交
No, you got yourself a deal!
-成交  成交  -成交  成交
- Deal! Deal!  - Deal! Deal!
成交
Deal.
七十二小时后见  哈哈
See you in 72 hours! Ha ha!
我们拭目以待谁能赚更多钱
We'll see who makes more money.
梅宝  你刚刚和一个专业骗子打了个赌吗
Mabel, did you just make a bet with a professional con man?
哦  拜托  做一个比斯坦更好的老板根本不在话下
Oh, come on. Being a better boss than Stan will be a cinch.
利润  我们来了
Profits, here we come!
-你把罐子摔了  -我会拿个新的
- You broke the jar. - We'll get a new one.
我想应该不用太担心
I guess I shouldn't be too worried.
我的意思是  斯坦在度假呢  他能赚多少钱啊
I mean, how much money could Stan even make on vacation?
先生  有什么事吗
Can I help you, sir?
我要从你的大转轮上卷走所有的钱
I'm here to take all the cash from your wheel.
派恩斯先生  你要见我们
You wanted to see us, mr. Pines?
斯坦已经不在了
Stan is no longer with us.
他死了  不  应该让我代他死啊
He's dead?! No! It should have been me!
喂  苏斯  斯坦没有死
Whoa, Soos. Stan's not dead.
他只是去度假三天
He's on vacation for three days.
我们打了个赌
We made a bet.
多谢你的澄清
Thank you for that clarification.
现在是梅宝掌大权
Mabel's in charge now!
那是垫肩吗
Are those shoulder pads?
对呀
Uh-huh!
这不过是我学到的先进管理技巧之一
It's just one of the many up-to-date managerial tricks
是从这本书上学的  它本来在厨房垫桌脚
I learned from this book I found propping up the kitchen table.
（成功管理学  1983）
为什么你的杯子上写“第二名”
Why does your mug say "NO.2"?
因为真正的第一名是你们
Because the real NO.1 is you.
-哈  我懂了  -励志啊
- Yeah, I get it. - Morale!
跟我来
Walk with me.
由我做老板  你们将发现这里出现了一些改变
With me as boss, you're gonna notice a few changes around here.
我的工作是帮助你们展现最好的“自己”
My job is to help you be your best "Selves."
满意
Satisfied.
每一天
Everyday.
爱生活
Loving life.
非常爱
Very much.
每一天
Everyday.
都满意
Satisfied.
到目前为止都听得很认真
Great listening here so far!
摇摇  接电话
Waddles, hold my calls.
秘书
好了  大家来讨论一下
All right, people, now rap with me.
温蒂  我该怎样才能更好地改进你的工作环境
Wendy, how can I make your workspace more Wendy-friendly?
嗯  斯坦从不让我在工作时和朋友一起玩
Hmm. Well, Stan never lets me hang out with friends at work.
斯坦不在  好姐妹  大门为你敞开
Stan ain't here, sister! Door's open!
太棒了
Sweet!
苏斯  我相信这是属于你的
And Soos,I believe this is yours.
问号君问问
Questiony the question mark?
我希望这是个感叹号  来表达我的激动之情
I wish this was an exclamation point to show how excited I am.
至于你  迪普
As for you, Dipper...
去死吧  狼人装
Die, wolf costume, die!
我要你现在就到林子里去
I want you to head into those woods and don't come back
不抓到惊人的神奇生物不准回来
until you've found an amazing attraction!
终于啊  是时候让斯坦看看真正的神秘猎人怎么做了
Finally! Time to show Stan how a real mystery hunter does it!
迪普去也
Dipper out!
好了  伙伴们  现在是证明好老板有好报的时候了
Okay, guys, it's time to prove that nice bosses finish first.
在接下来的四十八小时里  我们要把这个罐子
In the next 48 hours, we're gonna fill up this jar
用六千亿美元填满
with six hundred billion dollars!
好哇  好哇
Yeah! Yeah!
等等  你知道钱是怎么用的吗
Wait. Do you know how money works?
当然了  摇摇  去下面的商店给我买杯拿铁
Of course. Waddles, run down to the shop and grab me a latte.
他是个饥肠辘辘的小家伙
He's a hungry little guy.
啊  这条队伍真是没完没了
Ahh. This line is taking forever.
是时候看我老人的力量了
Time to use my old man powers.
啊  我心脏病犯了
Aaah! I'm having a heart attack!
唯一能治好的方法就是成为参赛者上节目
And the only cure is to be a contestant on--
吸金大转盘
On cash wheel!
行行好给我个名额  我年纪大了
Oh! Someone give me a part! I'm old.
要我们护送他出去吗
Should we escort him off the lot?
这人真是自我中心  引人注目不择手段
That man is a self-centered attention hog
简直没有人类尊严的底线
with no regard for human decency.
让他上电视
Get him on tv!
哦耶  宝贝加油
Whoa, yeah, come on girl
戴垫肩
Shoulder pads
奶昔
赚大钱
Make that money
现在梅宝当老板
Mabel's the boss now
利润
宝贝  向前走
Walk in, girl
让他们看看
Show them boys
利润
-赚大钱  -打卡签到
- Make that money...  - Time cards.
打卡签到
Time cards.
老板  老板  老板  老板  老板
Boss, boss, boss, boss, boss!
领导力
美极了
It's beautiful!
哇  你们的展览还真惊人
Wow, this is some freak show you got.
（全新管理）
谢谢你们  下次见
Thank you! See you soon!
告诉他们是梅宝送你的
Tell 'em Mabel sent you!
梅宝  我抓到好东西了
Mabel, I captured something!
这会让那些观光客大开眼界的
This is gonna blow those tourists away!
了不起的工作  有价值的员工
Marvelous work, valued employee.
哦  那是谁
Oh! Who's that?
是问号君问问吗
Is it questiony the question mark?
梅宝  我开始怀疑起这个主意了
Ah, I'm starting to have second thoughts about this, Mabel.
我总是忘记台词
I keep forgetting my lines,
而且这套服装  呃  比我的预期暴露了点
and this costume is more, uh, revealing than I expected.
苏斯  不要放弃
Soos, don't give up.
一切皆有可能  只要你
Anything is possible when you...
展开想象
"Imaginize it."
但我不明白那是什么意思
But I don't know what that means.
嘘
Shh!
别出声
Shh...
相信你自己
Believe in yourself.
但  但我
But--but I--
哦  真的  很冷
Oh, so--so cold.
我最爱的温蒂如何啊
How's my favorite wendy?
对  就这样  不  小心  小心
Yeah. Okay, all right. No. Look out. Look out.
耶  不要停
Yeah! Keep it goin'!
哦  这是什么
Oh, what's this?
比利
Billy!
你的脸  破相了
Your face! It's ruined!
我真的很抱歉  请接受退款
I'm so sorry. Please, have a refund.
温蒂  看来你有很多打扫工作要做
Wendy, you've got a lot of cleaning up to do.
劳驾
Please?
哇  这些古板的规定
Whoa. All this rule stuff
开始让你听起来像斯坦一样了
is starting to make you sound like Stan.
什么  不  我一点儿也不像斯坦
What?! No, I'm nothing like Stan!
那个  今天剩下的时间给你放假
In fact, take the rest of the day off.
-带全薪的  -当然
- With full pay?  - Of course.
梅宝・派恩斯  你是史上最好的老板
Mabel Pines, you are the best boss ever.
我是问号君问问哦  啊哈
I'm questiony the question mark! Aaah!
哦  不要  辣得够呛啊
Aaah! Oh, don't! It stings so bad!
女士们和先生们  欢迎来到
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to...
吸金大转轮
Cash wheel!
现在让我们认识一下参赛者们
Now let's meet those contestants.
我是道格  来自加州的费尔菲德
I'm Doug, from Fairfield, California.
我是唐纳  来自
I'm Donna, from--
我是斯坦  斯坦・派恩斯  哈哈
I'm Stan! Stan Pines! Ha ha!
难道  不是已经介绍过我了吗  你好  我是斯坦
Did we--did we already do me? Hello? I'm Stan!
呵呵  好的
Heh heh. Okay.
各位  看来今晚会是个漫漫长夜
Well, it's gonna be a long night, folks.
是时候来解决
It's time to solve--
来开始  嗯  解决谜题吧
It's, uh, time to solve that puzzle.
-卡拉  -好的  里奇
- Carla.  - Yes, Rich?
里面是不是有S
Are there any "S's"?
实际上  现在还没到你呢
Actually, it's not your turn yet--
我准备好攻克难题了
I'm ready to solve!
不  游戏还没开始呢
No. The game hasn't started.
是不是  闭上你的嘴
Is it "Shut your yaps"?
好样的
Well played.
钞票浴  钞票浴  钞票浴
Cash shower, cash shower, cash shower...
钞票浴
Cash shower!
好啊
Yes! Da da doo.
派恩斯先生  哦不  你没必要脱掉衣服
Mr. Pines. No, you don't need to take your clothes off--
不  进广告  快进广告
No--go to commercial. Go to commercial!
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen--
我的名字是诚实迪普  并且  不像我的骗子叔公
My name's honest Dipper, and, unlike my cheating uncle,
我有真东西展示给你们  绝对不是恶作剧
I have something to show you that isn't a hoax.
把这家伙关进笼子时  它差点杀了我
It nearly killed me getting him into that cage.
看吧  一半魔鬼  一半妖怪的
Behold! Part gremlin, part goblin--
魔妖怪
The gremloblin!
哦  这个好玩儿
Well, that's fun.
这是假的  亲爱的  你看线头都出来了
It's fake, honey. You can see the strings.
什么  它们不是线  是体毛啊
What?! Those aren't strings! That's body hair!
啊  快看这个  亲爱的
Ah, look at this, dear.
六块腹肌羚
The six-pack-o-lope.
（注：羚羊为antelope）
哈哈  好双关
Ha ha! Wordplay!
不  这儿别的东西都是假的
No! Everything else here is fake!
这个才是真正超自然的野兽
This is a real paranormal beast.
嘿  关于这小家伙一个有趣的事
Hey! Fun fact about this little guy:
盯着它的眼睛  就能看到你们最恐怖的噩梦
You look into his eyes, you can see your worst nightmare.
惊呆了  对吧  该给小费了
Amazing, right? I work for tips.
再次感谢光临
Thanks again for visiting!
谢谢购物啦
Thanks for shopping with us.
我来处理
I'll get that!
来为您服务
Here ya go.
抱歉  请接收退款  这就是梅宝的特色
Sorry! Have refunds! That's the Mabel difference!
好吧  我刚刚把两个人弄疯了
Well, I just made two people go insane.
-你怎么样呢  -我好累啊
- How about you?  - I'm so tired.
我放了温蒂的假  所以我就得做她的活儿
I gave wendy the day off, so I had to do her job.
那么  或许你需要
Well, maybe you need to
对大家更严厉一点儿
start being a little bit tougher around here.
不可能  斯坦才会那样做
No way! That's what Stan would do!
我只需要积极思考  与人为善
I just need to think positive, be friendly,
然后一切都会好起来的
and everything will work out fine.
怎么会这样  它是怎么逃出上锁的笼子的
What? How did he get out of his locked cage?!
这个嘛
Well...
（你可以休息五分钟哦  -梅宝）
你竟然还给它休息时间了
You gave him a break?!
它也是员工啊  从某种程度上来说吧
He's an employee! Sort of.
我们得赶快围捕它  苏斯在哪儿
We gotta round him up. Where's Soos?
他太紧张了
He was stressed out,
所以我让他舒缓地漫步自然去了
so I told him to take a soothing nature walk.
有人么  文明世界吗
Hello? Civilization?
狗狗
Doggy?
女士们先生们  斯坦・派恩斯毫无悬念地
Ladies and gentlemen, Stan Pines is poised
成为我们的超级冠军
to become our grand champion!
有没有什么要对粉丝说的呢
Anything to say to your fans out there?
明晚见  梅宝
See you tomorrow night, Mabel!
我们该怎么办
What do we do?!
它在奖励自己根本不应得到的小贴画
He's awarding himself stickers that he didn't even earn!
呃  有了  和一个魔妖怪打斗时  使用水
Uh, got it. "When fighting a gremloblin, use water...
那是迫不得已的手段
"...only as a last resort,
因为水会让它更加  更加可怕
as water will make him much, much scarier."
啊  谁说话这么大喘气啊
Aah! Who writes sentences like that?!
别担心  它最终还是会走的
Don't worry. He's gotta leave eventually.
我是会唱歌的大马哈鱼  整天都在唱歌
I'm the singin' salmon spendin' all day jammin'.
天哪  它为什么就是不走呢
Ohh! Why doesn't he just leave?
-我们的收入啊  -梅宝  等等
- Our profits!  - Mabel, wait!
停住  停下来
Stop! Stop!
别盯着它邪恶的眼睛
Don't look into his evil eye!
你会看见你最最可怕的梦靥
You'll see your worst nightmare!
我倒希望有双邪恶的眼睛  让它看看到底什么是噩梦
I wish we had an evil eye to show him!
哦  不
Oh, no! Aahh....
等等  嘿  魔怪
Wait. Hey, monster!
看看这个吧
Take a look at this!
你成了你父亲那样的人
呃  至少它没有造成太大的破坏
Well, at least he didn't do that much damage.
哦  天啊
Oh, boy.
迪普  已经是第三天了
Dipper, it's the third day.
我们只有七个小时赚回我们的收入了
We've only got seven hours to earn back our profits
不然整个夏天我就得穿印着失败者T恤了
Or I've gotta wear that "Loser" Shirt all summer!
嗨  大伙儿  是我发疯了
Hey, guys. Am I nuts,
还是这个地方变得完全不一样了
or does this place look different?
温蒂  苏斯  我见到你们真是太开心了
Wendy! Soos! Am I glad to see you.
我们还有很多事要做  但如果我们加把劲
We've got a lot of work to do, but if we hurry,
我们还是能够打败斯坦的
We can still beat Stan!
呃  是啊  但我有点头疼
Uh, yeah. I got a little headache,
所以我能不能  那个  今天不上班
So maybe I should, like, not work today.
其实我刚刚遇到了一群狼
And I actually just met this pack of wolves,
我觉得它们大概是想要抚养我
And I think they're gonna, like,
就像对待自己的孩子一样
raise me as one of their own?
所以我现在真的该去洞穴里了
So I should really be at the den right now.
但  但是
But--but--
可是  嘿  周一见了
But, hey, we'll see you on monday.
呃  有谁要吃这个吗
Uh, is anyone gonna eat these?
够了
Enough!!!
我受够了
I have had it!
我为了拯救这摊生意  去和怪物搏斗
I fought a monster to save this business,
而你们就是这么回报我的吗
And this is how you repay me?!
你们这些吊儿郎当的人气得我肝儿颤
I'm gonna get an ulcer from your lollygagging!
-吊儿郎当  -肝儿颤
- Lollygagging?  - Ulcer?
你表现得  不一样了
You're acting... different.
闭上你的臭嘴
You shut your yaps!
我做了每个人的活儿
I've been doing everyone's jobs
然而你们却统统把我榨干了
while you've both been bleeding me dry!
-可是  -别“可是”了  赶快给我去打扫地板
- But-- - No "Buts" except yours on the floor, cleaning!
-别游手好闲的  快去工作  -遵命  梅宝
- Now quit loafing and get to work!  - Yes, Mabel.
应该是  遵命  老板
That's "Yes, boss."
迪普  我都变成什么了
Dipper! What have I become?
你必须这么做  梅宝  你必须这么做
What you had to, Mabel... what you had to.
我们还有七小时来扭转乾坤
We've got seven hours to turn this around!
伙计们  行动起来吧
Let's go, people!
你转到了“钞票洪水”
You landed on "Cash flood"!
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha ha!
我一毛钱都不会捐给慈善机构的
I'm givin' none of this to charity!
那么现在你可以选择回家  成为一个富翁
And now you can go home a thousandaire...
或者你可以赌一把  得到现在双倍的钱
Or you could risk everything to double your money
额外加分猜词就行
with the bonus word!
里奇  我是个普通人
Rich, I'm a simple man.
所以我要带上我的战利品  收拾好我的包  然后
So I'm gonna take my winnings, pack my bags, and...
把它们全赌在加分猜词上
Bet them all on the bonus word!
来吧
Come on!
时间就是金钱  戴安全帽的
Time is money, hardhats!
你有什么怨言  向投诉部门说去吧
You got complaints, file 'em with the complaint department!
哎呀  我的小腰
Ohh! My back!
迪普  九点钟方向有观光客
Dipper! We got tourists at nine o'clock!
可我该给他们看什么呢  真的魔物只会把他们吓跑
What do I show them? Real magic just freaks people out.
自己动脑筋想想啊  笨蛋
Figure something out, knucklehead!
女游客和男游客们
Ladies and gentletourists,
这个小屋充满着
This shack is filled with
从未被凡人目睹的奇迹
wonders never before seen by human eyes!
可怕的巨型问号宝宝
The horrible giant question baby!
我是成人  还是宝宝呢
Am I a man? Am I a baby?
这些都是合理的问题
These are legitimate questions.
和问号大宝合照  只要一块钱
Have your picture taken with it for a buck.
十块钱  一百块
Uh, ten bucks. A hundred bucks!
我们对您的快乐时光不予退款啊
We put the fun in "No refunds."
-我们干得如何  -我们装满了一整个罐子
- How'd we do?  - We filled the whole jar!
减去替换所有家具的钱
Minus the money to replace all the furniture
还有维修小屋的支出  那么我们还剩
And supplies to fix the shack, that leaves us..
一块钱
One dollar.
-滴答滴答  时间到了  孩子们  -哦  不要
- Tick-tock! Time's up, kids!  - Oh, no!
看到我离开后你们都穿戴整齐真开心
Nice to see you learned how to dress while I was gone.
你赢了我们多少
How much did you beat us by?
我赢得了三十万美金
I won $300,000!
然后
And then...
一个使你的钱翻倍的机会  也可能全盘皆输
For a chance to double your cash or lose it all,
当你礼貌地询问某事  用的六个字母的单词是什么
What is a six-letter word you use to ask for something politely?
举例来说 “空格  我可以看看吗”
For example, "May I blank have that?"
我看起来像个傻瓜吗  观众们
Do I look like an idiot, folks?
那个词就是 “给我” 两个E
The word is "gimmee." twe E's.
哦  你看  因为你好不容易走到这步
Oooh! You know, because you've gone this far,
我们将再给你一次机会
We're gonna give you one more chance.
再试一次  是个以P开头的词
Let's try again. It's a "P" Word.
有人甚至认为这是一个魔法词汇
Some might even say it's the "Magic word."
阿布拉卡达布拉  最终答案
Abracadabra! Final answer!
我很遗憾  斯坦  但是那个词是
I'm sorry, Stan, but the word is...
劳驾
"Please."
显然那个词真能让你赚大钱
Apparently that word can make you money.
所以  等等  如果你输了一切
So, wait. If you lost everything,
那么就意味着  梅宝  你赢了
Then that means-- Mabel! You won!
哇  我们成功了
Whoo! We did it!
等会儿  我们又赢了什么呢
Wait. What do we win again?
根据我们之前打的赌
Well, according to our bet,
看来梅宝是新任老板了
I guess Mabel's the new boss?
-不  不要  千万别那样  -啊  什么
- No! No! Don't do that!  - Huh? What?
斯坦叔公  我不知道原来老板这么不好当
Grunkle Stan, I had no idea how hard it was being boss.
这地方都乱成一锅粥了
This place was cuckoo bananas
直到我开始像你那样对别人乱喊乱叫
until I started barking orders at people like you.
好吧  我得承认
Yeah, well, I got to admit,
回来真好  你们懂吗
It's kind of nice to be back, ya know?
好了  够了  走远点儿
Okay, okay, that's enough, get offa me!
那么苏斯  温蒂
And Soos, Wendy...
工作去
Get to work!
咳咳  劳驾  还是会难受
Ahem. Please. Uhh! Still hurts.
梅宝  你们达成的协议是不是说
Mabel, didn't your agreement say something about
斯坦输了的话就要跳某种道歉舞
Stan having to do some kind of apology dance if he lost?
没有  没  肯定没说
N-no. No, it didn't.
实际上  是的  我记得我的笔记里写过这条
Actually, yeah, I think I have it in my notes here.
不要  那是不可能的
No! That never happened!
哈哈  我去拿相机
Ha ha! I'll get the camera!
跳就跳  让我先
All right, let me just--
斯坦叔公
Grunkle Stan!
听着  我是不会
Uhh. Look, I'm not gonna--
快跳
Do it!
我是斯坦  我错了
I'm Stan, and I was wrong
我唱着这首斯坦道歉歌
I'm singing "The Stan wrong song"
我不该贪心打那个赌
I shouldn't have taken that chance
所以我现在跳着忏悔舞
Now here's my remorseful dance
踢脚
Do the kicks!
花哨点儿
Jazzier!
嘿  快给我
Hey, gimme that!
哎呦  我的老腰
Ow! My back!
你认为如何
What do you think?
第三十遍
Take thirty!